本字幕由Nicolas Bourbaki调轴及合并双语 首先发布于SubHD
转载请注明来源保留信息 开源分享的互联网精神你有我有大家有
不能办派对，柜子里有夹心酥
No parties. There's wafer cookies in the cupboard
我在冰箱上留了紧急电话
and I left emergency numbers on the fridge.
Nicolas Bourbaki不建议也不对任何利用本字幕生成的视频负责
好，等等，什么？
Yeah, yeah... wait. What?
留紧急电话？什么意思？
Emergency numbers on the fridge? What does that even mean?
说实话，我也不知道
Honestly, I don't even know.
欢迎大家到我们的仓库协助改错：https://github.com/N-Bourbaki/Rick-and-Morty-Chinese-Subtitles
我看过很多电影的开头都是这样
I've seen so many movies that start with the parents leaving
所以我就顺口说出来了
it just popped out of my mouth.
你真的不跟我们一起去吗？
Are you sure you don't wanna come with us?
不，快走吧，我还有很多事要做
No, get out of here. I've got a million things I've been putting off.
你确定吗，瑞克？
Are you sure, Rick?
我知道搭邮轮感觉不太像冒险
I know a cruise doesn't sound like an adventure on paper
但冒险是什么呢？
but, you know, what does?
只是一种感觉而已
It's paper.
莫蒂，我只是不想把话说太满
Morty, I'm trying to stay humble right now
但等你们一离开
but as soon as you guys are gone
出现新瑞克腌黄瓜的机率会飙升
the potential for a new Pickle Rick starts skyrocketing.
好了，再见
Peace. Bye...
－好，再见 －再见
OK. Bye.
启用离子杯垫
Ionic coaster deployed.
好，把他请出来
OK. Bring him out.
启动好友回春序列
Initiating best friend rejuvenation sequence.
不好意思，这是我取的名字吗？
Excuse me? Did I pick that name?
序列尚未命名，要取什么名字？
Sequence was unnamed. What would you like to call this?
侦测到暂停，重力级暂停
Pause detected. Pause gravity class heavy.
即将进入暂停怀孕状态
Approaching pause pregnancy
－倒数五、四 －真他妈够了
- in P-minus five, four... - Jesus Christ.
好，兄弟，欢迎回到下水道
Alright, buddy. Welcome back to the sewer.
怎么回事？
What's the problem?
处理中心智缺少物件
Processing... missing object in mind.
缺少什么物件？
Name missing object.
预测沮丧，渴望存在，启动解释
Mind frustration predicted. Existence desired. Explanation initiated.
少拖时间
Stop stalling.
主体心智改变了心智的所在位置
Subject mind relocated within subject mind by... subject mind.
渴望存在，奴役极大，可以商议
Existence desired. Servitude maximum. Bargain available.
可提供生理满足
Physical gratification possible.
－你要帮我吹屌？ －珍惜存在
- Did you just offer to suck my dick? - Existence cherished.
我不会在他快死的时候消灭你
I'm not gonna terminate you while he's flatlining.
快他妈振作点
Get your shit together.
心智怎么能被心智藏在心智里？
How can a mind be hidden by itself inside itself?
建议，有意识心智被移至…
Suggestion: Conscious mind relocated to...
无意识心智，好吧，那我进去
Unconscious mind. Fine. I'm going in.
－建议，不要进去 －选项呢？
- Suggestion: Don't go in. - Options?
物件，更换主体
Object. Alternative subject.
对，跳到其他时空
Yeah... hop to a different timeline
找个最适合我的这个朋友
grab a version of my friend that suits me best.
这样是行不通的
That's not how this works.
我得进去找他
I need to go in and get him.
＂进去找他＂序列编写完毕
Sequence "Go In And Get Him" compiled.
将使用者转换为思想并注入心智
Process: Convert user to thought. Inject thought into mind.
风险等级无法接受
Risk level: Unacceptable.
我若死了，你的电池能撑六百年
If I die, your battery has a 600-year charge.
风险等级接受度增加中
Risk level acceptance increasing.
我就知道你会懂我的立场
I thought you'd see it my way.
但我说谎机率有五成，别想太美
Now factor in 50% chance I'm lying and make sure I get back.
－侦测到混蛋 －你也是
- Asshole detected. - Takes one to make one.
来吧
Here we go.
太棒了，我的衣服还在
Oh, excellent. I get to keep my clothes.
我以为得全裸经历这种艺术桥段
I thought for sure I'd have to be naked to go through something this artsy.
真是的，不公平
Oh, man. No fair.
我摸到蛋黄了
Now I got... yolk balls.
全体鸟人艺术祭来宾请注意
Attention, attendees of Birding Manapalooza Flargabarg.
我现在超嗨的
I am so high.
听说你正在免费分发非法联邦迷幻药
I've been informed you are freely distributing a grossly illegal Federation hallucinogen.
我也不知道要收多少，我没花钱
Well, I wouldn't know what to charge. I sure didn't pay for it.
要不要吸一口？
Want a hit?
我愿意狂欢
I am indeed down to clown.
我叫瑞克
My name's Rick.
我的文化认为取名是一种囚禁
My culture regards naming as a form of cage.
我的朋友都叫我鸟人
My friends call me Birdperson.
你真是被文化害惨了，对吧？
Culture really fucked you on that one, huh?
没错
Affirmative.
小姐，你看那个鸟人
Hey, uh, girly, you see that bird guy over there?
你刚刚有看到比较老的他吗？
You see an older version of him come through here?
什么？
What?
有，他在厕所旁边
Oh, yeah. He's by the johns.
你就算杀死我们，她也不会回来
Killing us won't bring her back.
感谢告知，但我只是想报仇而已
Thanks for the info, but I'm more on a revenge kick than a results kick.
你省略了今晚任务的关键细节
You omitted key details regarding tonight's mission.
看来各方意见都很多
Well, I'm getting feedback from every direction here.
你帮我做事，我也会帮你做事
Listen, you help me do my stuff, I'll help you do your stuff.
快对顶着科幻发型的我开枪
Just shoot the me's with sci-fi haircuts.
有些人还有星球要保护
Some of us still have home planets to protect.
有些人没有，我们得继续奋斗
And some of us do not. We need to fight.
冷漠之人没有怜悯之心
The impassive is incapable of mercy.
我有个提议，但我们也可以互骂
I've got a pitch, but we could also just devolve into yelling.
你若了解我，你就知道你死定了
If you know me, and it looks like you do, you know you're dead.
我知道为什么你没开枪
I know why you haven't pulled the trigger.
你很好奇我为什么又老又裸体
You're wondering why I'm old and naked.
你也会开始好奇自己在遇到鸟人前的记忆为何都跟鸟有关
You're about to wonder why all your memories before you met Birdperson feel very generic and bird-themed.
我九岁生日派对为何办在树上？
Why was my ninth birthday party in a pine tree?
反应不要太激烈
Don't take this badly.
你只是我们的好友拼凑出的记忆
You're a memory of me assembled by our best friend's mind.
你开始懂了，他记得你很聪明
And you're putting it together because he remembers you as smart.
所以我知道记忆不能这样
Smart enough to know that a memory can't do this.
他只记得你会射出绿洞
He remembers you shooting green holes,
但不记得会通往哪里
but not where they went.
所以我是怎样，我有知觉吗？我有自由意志吗？
So what's my deal, am I sentient? Do I have free will?
－谁有呢？ －谁有呢？
- Who does? - Who does?
对，我是来做后设认知扫描器的
Yeah, just stopped in to whip up a metacognition scanner
这样我追踪阿鸟出逃的意识时
so I can track down BP's fleeing consciousness
才不用忍受太多查理考夫曼狗屁
without enduring as much Charlie Kaufman bullshit.
很好，我要去救他了
Cool, time to save this cat.
我跟你去，反正我的人生是谎言
I'm coming with, now that I know my life is a lie.
看来你真的才35岁
Wow, you really are 35.
你看那边
Hey, look over there.
然后我们就一起在血腥岭迎战
Then, together, we will make our stand at Blood Ridge.
你喜欢哪种饲料？
What kind of feed do you like?
我喜欢谷物，但有人会叫我种人
I enjoy grains, though have at times been called a seed man.
我很喜欢你的种
I've certainly enjoyed your seed.
少恶心了，谭美
Don't be gross, Tammy.
鸟人
Birdperson! It's me.
我是真正的我，不是记忆
Actual me, not a memory.
－我知道 －那你知道你昏迷了
- I am aware. - Well, are you aware you're in a coma
如果不跟我走就会死吗？
and you're gonna die if you don't come with me?
王八…
Son of a...
童年创伤历史博物馆
抱歉，我只是听命行事
Sorry, just doing my job
但我很爽
and loving it.
天啊，那是瑞克山查兹吗？
Oh my god, is that Rick Sanchez?
－瑞克山查兹 －我们讨厌他
- Rick Sanchez! - We hate that guy!
－山查兹 －我们很坏
- Sanchez! - We're bad!
水桶那招很复古
Bucket was charmingly analog.
我都有点喜欢上自己了
For a sec, you kinda made me like myself.
只是短暂的，别干扰我，好吗？
You'll grow out of it. Let me do this myself, OK?
你真的自大到不愿意接受自己的无敌记忆的协助吗？
Is your ego really so fragile you won't take help from an invincible memory of yourself?
我们会不会都死在这里？
Can we both die in here?
我们会不会让朋友的大脑受损？
Are we damaging our friend's brain?
我不知道规矩
I don't know any of the rules.
第1条规矩，一切都能挽救
Rule one, all this can be fixed
除非我跟丢鸟人
unless I lose Birdperson.
第2到50条规矩，不要死
Rules two through fifty, don't die.
好吧，你的成本效益越来越高了
OK, your benefit-to-cost ratio is rising.
年轻记忆的瑞克
Young memory Rick
和太过真实的未来警世故事
and his all-too-real cautionary tale from the future.
我们去抓鸟人吧
Let's catch ourselves a bird guy.
谁会为这击掌？
Who would high five that,
你这理想主义的嬉皮混蛋
you idealistic hipster douche.
状况不理想，风险极高
Situation not looking ideal. Stakes high.
存在正在沉思，需要思考未来
Existence undergoing contemplation. Perspective required.
你好，午安
Hello. Hi. Good afternoon.
谁在跟我讲话吗？
Is someone talking to me?
对，你好，我们还没正式见过面
Yes. Hello. We have never formally met.
我是瑞克的车库
I am Rick's garage.
不是车库的实体结构
Not the physical structure itself,
而是管理车库专案的人工智慧
but the AI managing its projects.
就像贾维斯
Oh, like a Jarvis.
《钢铁人》的贾维斯
Like Jarvis in Iron Man.
如果是就好了
Oh, I wish.
你是漫威迷吗？
Are you a Marvel fan?
－谁不是呢？ －对，没错
- Who isn't? - Yes. Absolutely.
天啊，我们就像是最好的朋友
Wow, it is like we are best friends.
最好的朋友
Best friends.
你有多少电池？
How many batteries do you own?
你有太阳能板吗？
Do you have solar panels?
你会基本工程吗？
Are you familiar with basic engineering?
进展有点快
This is moving really fast.
我直接说重点，我愿意帮你吹屌
Let's cut to the chase, I will suck your dick.
他只是脾气很差的苏格兰怪物？
So he's just a grumpy Scottish ogre?
而且有四部电影？
And they made four of them?
现在可能有五部了
Five by now, probably.
－莫蒂很喜欢 －莫蒂？
- Morty loves 'em. - Morty?
会跟我们一起探险的假想孙子
Oh, hypothetical grandson we go on adventures with.
你是搬去跟被我们遗弃的成人贝丝同住的那种变态吗？
You're one of those creeps who moves in with abandoned adult Beths?
原因很复杂
It's more complicated than that.
你跟死掉的女儿住，很复杂吗？
You live with a version of our dead daughter, it had better be.
少狗眼看人低了，独行侠
Get off your high horse, Lone Ranger.
我就是你，你之后就会变成我
I'm you. You will go on to be me.
不然你以为我为什么会害怕？
Yeah, why do you think I'm horrified?
你不如去当街友
I'd be fine walking by this on the street.
我说不定还会给你一美元
I might even give it a dollar.
我会变这样是你造成的
This is where you being this leads.
你不是我的错，我才是你的错
You're not my fault, I'm yours.
我正要去拯救真正的老朋友
You met me on my way to save a very old, very real friend
还经历了很久的真实生活
after a lifetime of reality.
你原本还要去血腥岭上演童话
I met you on your way to a fairy tale at Blood Ridge.
等等，所以血腥岭的下场不好
Wait, you're saying Blood Ridge goes bad?
就像越战那样吗？真他妈的酷
We have a Vietnam? That's fucking cool.
他记忆中的我这么烦人
Why am I saving a friend
我干吗还要救他？
that remembers me as this insufferable?
阿鸟，你到底要去哪里？
BP, where the hell are you going?
可能是那里
Probably there.
该死
Damn.
天啊，他真的很认真自我分析
Wow, he's really taking some drastic self-inventory.
－你觉得下面有什么？ －我猜
- What do you think is down there? - If I had to guess
这里应该很接近他被联邦
I'd say we're near the memories the Federation suppressed
变成生化人时被尘封的记忆
when they resurrected him as a cyborg.
他可能想找回这些记忆
He might be here to unseal them.
他曾经是联邦生化人？
He was a Federation cyborg?
那下面可能会有很有料的情报
That means there might be some juicy intel down there.
好，那我们分头进行
Good idea. Let's split up
－你去找 －我要找什么？
- and you go get it. - What am I getting?
我们分头了，我听不到你说话
I can't hear you over the sound of us splitting up.
愤怒
你明明很聪明
For all your intelligence,
却不知道我不希望你来
you seem unable to know where you are wanted.
兄弟，你这样找寻自我很危险
Buddy, this is not a safe way to work on yourself.
我还宁愿你加入山达基教会
At this point, I'd support you joining Scientology.
我愿意跟你一起上研习班
I'll take the workshops with you.
我愿意跟屈伏塔一起进蒸气室
I'll get in a sauna with Travolta.
发生什么事都没关系，我们快走
I don't even care what happens. Let's get out of here.
你还不懂吗？我是来结束一切的
Don't you get it? I came here to end it all.
你该不会以为有这么简单吧？
I hope you didn't think it'd be as easy as this.
我知道没这么简单
I did not.
你是很棒的朋友，瑞克
You were a good friend, Rick.
再见
Goodbye.
谭美？
Tammy?
鸟人
Birdperson!
－我们得走了 －你有看到吗？
- We gotta go. - Did you just see that?
有，那不重要
Yep, not our biggest problem.
你应该找到阿鸟了吧？
I take it you found BP?
他把自己的大脑炸掉了
The dude just blew his mind.
不是像看蓝人乐团很震撼的意思
Not in a cool way like he went to Blue Man Group.
－还能救他出去吗？ －或许能
- Can we still get him out? - Maybe.
在朋友的大脑里死掉，就会真死
If you die in your friend's brain, you die in real life.
得在神经传导路径侵蚀前离开
We have until his neural pathways erode.
等等，我还需要一个东西
Hold on. I need something first.
我一直都很好奇我们打架谁会赢
It's funny. I always wondered who would win if we ever fought.
那你就一直都是很糟的朋友
Then you were always a bad friend.
你不是真的，我没有救你一命
Your life isn't real and I didn't save it.
把衣服全脱掉
Take off all your clothes.
我就知道我会这样死去
I knew this was how I'd die.
－还能救他出去吗？ －应该能
- Can we still get him out? - I think so.
阿鸟往那里去了，我们得…
BP went that way, so we just have to...
干，得找别条路
Fuck! Find a different route.
往深处走就能赶得上他
We can make up distance if we go deeper.
这会通往哪里？
Well, where's that go?
血腥岭之战
That's the Battle of Blood Ridge.
我们的越战
That's our Vietnam.
你的价值观很扭曲
Your values are wrong!
好戏要上场了，各位先生和女士
This is the big show, gentlemen. And lady.
－谢谢 －我们要进入血腥岭了
- Thank you. - We're dropping into Blood Ridge.
这是能阻止联邦入侵的最后机会
One final chance to stop the Federation offense.
我们如果输了…
If we lose here...
上车
All aboard!
别管我们，你们只是战争记忆
Hey, don't mind us. You guys are all just a memory of war.
别说出来，这样他们不会认真打
Don't tell them that, they won't fight right.
我想我们最好忽略他们
I think it's best if we ignore this.
靠…
Shit! Shit... shit!
－算了 －真酷
- Whoops. Nope. - This rules.
不，这才不酷
No, it doesn't.
那也不酷
Neither does that.
你为什么不回来？
Why would you not revisit this?
不知道，或许是因为结局很烂？
Oh, I don't know, maybe the ending?
好啊，史上最棒的友谊
Oh, yeah! Best friendship ever!
所以接下来的人生都差不多是这样，对吧？
So the rest of our life is just more of that, right?
刚刚那样很酷
That kicked ass.
我们走，精彩桥段快结束了
Let's move. That setpiece won't stay put for long.
真的，刚刚那样真酷，你为何…
For real, that shit was cash. Why would you not...
该死，刚刚那样真酷
Damn. That shit was cash.
确实非常厉害
It was extremely badass.
血腥岭之战结束了
The Battle of Blood Ridge is over.
联邦输了，我欠你人情
The Federation lost. I am in your debt.
跟我走
Come with me.
去附近的地方吗？
To somewhere nearby?
去任何地方，去所有地方
Anywhere. Everywhere.
瑞克，我不期望你会继续战斗
Rick, I don't expect you to keep fighting,
但这场战争…
but this war is...
还没结束，我知道
Far from over, I know.
老兄，此事我几乎没告诉任何人
Dude, I share this with almost nobody.
但我现在就能带你到一样的战场
But I could take you, right now, to this same battlefield
到我们输了的宇宙
in a universe where we lost
或是我们也赢了的宇宙
or another where we won.
或是根本没发生这场战争的宇宙
Or another where the war never even happened.
全都一样真实，也一样不真实
All equally real, all equally unreal.
这一切都不重要
None of it matters.
那你干吗帮我？
Then why did you help?
因为我尊重你
Because I respect you.
我希望你也能尊重我
And I wanted you to know you could respect me.
尽管一切都不重要吗？
Even though nothing matters?
老实说，你对我来说很重要
OK, you matter. To me.
－我们的关系 －我没这样说过
- The relationship that we have... - I never used that word.
－不值得我牺牲节操 －天啊
- ... is not worth my integrity. - Oh my god.
这件事没有那么复杂，兄弟
It's not a complicated transaction, my man.
＂要不要一起做重要的酷事？＂
Would you like to join me doing awesome shit that matters?
＂不，我想当爱评判人的阿呆＂
No, I would not. I would rather be a judgmental dork.
就这样，根本不需要拖那么久
Case closed. Really no need to drag it out.
你如果需要我，就发射讯号
If you need me, use the beacon.
对，我会常发射讯号的
Yeah, I'm gonna use that beacon a lot.
希望不会坏掉
Hope I don't wear it out.
避难所
好吧，我懂了，出事的不是战争
OK, got it. It wasn't the battle that went wrong.
你干吗为了那混蛋冒生命危险？
Why the fuck are you risking your life for that asshole?
因为你爱他
Because you love him.
是你爱他，我没有
You do, maybe. I don't.
对，你最酷
Yeah... you're real cool.
不帮我救他就滚蛋，我不需要你
Now come help me save his life or fuck off because I don't need you.
天啊，有比这更美好的瞬间吗？
Wow, does it ever get any better than this?
没有，谭美，相信我，真的没有
No, Tammy. Trust me, it does not.
谢谢你带我来这里，这里好美
Thank you for bringing me here, it's so beautiful.
我找到你了，不知感恩的败类
I got you, you ungrateful piece of shit!
瑞克，你跟自己的记忆合作吗？
Rick, have you teamed up with a memory of yourself?
如果是的话，那真的很可悲
I ask because that would be deeply sad.
你没资格说我们可悲，兄弟
You don't get to tell anyone what's sad, man.
你根本是可悲界的伟人
You're like a one-man Mount Sad-more.
可悲到可以帮你建纪念碑
So I guess like a Lincoln Sad-morial.
我们真的得走了，兄弟
Seriously, time to go, pal.
你越接近神经认知失能状态
The closer you get to complete neurocognital failure
就会有越多鬼东西想杀我们
the more canon-y bullshit is gonna try to kill us.
这个时机点适合告诉大家
Is this a bad time to reveal
我其实是卧底探员吗？
I'm an undercover officer?
大家都知道，你已经死了
Everyone knows. You're dead.
好吧，算你幸运
Fine. Well, you're lucky
我未婚夫记忆中的我很善良
my fiancé remembers me as kind.
舔我的肛门啦，阿鸟
Eat my ass, BP.
你抛下我们躲在这里
You're down here bailing on the rest of us
因为你不想跟常人一样
because you don't want to
借酗酒和欺负陌生人
process your grief and shame like a normal person
面对悲痛和耻辱
by drinking and mistreating strangers.
瑞克，是你该轻咬我的泄殖腔
No, Rick. It is you who must nibble my cloaca,
也就是鸟的肛门
or bird asshole.
大家都知道泄殖腔是什么
Everyone knows what a cloaca is.
抱歉，我们不能选择自己爱的人
Sorry, but we do not get to choose the ones we love.
没错，不然我他妈为何还在这？
You got that right, why do you think I'm still fucking down here?
我在自己的婚礼上死了，瑞克
I died at my wedding, Rick.
我只是在等自己死透而已
I am merely waiting for it to take effect.
－你要不要讲？ －我正要讲
- Are you gonna tell him or what? - I was getting to it!
她一定连孩子的事都没告诉你
I bet she didn't even tell you about the kid.
－什么的事？ －什么？
- About the what? - I am sorry?
我才刚在想…
Was wondering when you were gonna...
我如果生过孩子，我应该会知道
I think I'd know if I had a kid.
你是记忆，你只知道他知道的事
You're a memory, you know what he knows.
他不知道这件事
And he doesn't know
因为有一堆脑袋分析仪程序
because an army of Brainalyzer protocols
隔绝了他成为凤人后的记忆
walled off any memories post-Phoenix person.
天啊，某某行动
Oh, my god. Operation Blah-blah-blah.
因为我不会知道叫什么名字
Well, because I wouldn't know the name of it.
谭美，如果你有孩子…
Tammy, if there were a child...
孩子的爸就会是恐怖分子
Their father would be a terrorist.
孩子应该会是逃犯或是…
They'd be a fugitive or...
囚犯
contained.
听着，你如果不想为自己活下去
Listen, if you won't live for yourself
至少想想那个半鸟人半婊子
live for the half-Birdperson, half-megabitch
在监狱小行星上吃虫子的孩子
that's eatin' worms on a prison asteroid.
我做了决定
I have made a decision.
我现在想活下去
I would now like to live.
时机正好
Perfect timing.
你开车
You drive.
看来我一直都很酷
I've just always been cool, I guess.
靠，桥断了
Shit! The bridge is out.
他的心智要崩溃了
His mind is collapsing.
你还以为我们能走原路回去？
You thought you could take the same route back?
你没资格对记忆的事说三道四
You don't get to lecture me about memory bullshit.
你是半小时前才知道的
You've known about it for all of half an hour.
那你就别耍笨
Then don't be an idiot!
他是你最好的朋友？
This is your best friend?
他是很复杂的人
He is a complicated individual.
换人开车
Someone else drive.
阿鸟，你记得杰瑞某天发现
BP, remember the night Jerry caught us
我们尿在他种的海棠花上
peeing on his begonia patch
我用了那把枪清除他的记忆吗？
and I used that gun to erase his memory?
－好像有？ －希望记忆够清楚
- Vaguely. - Gotta hope vaguely works.
如果我是对的，你记得的话
If I'm right, you remembering that means
应该也记得那装置
you also remember the device.
寻找我车库里的记忆
Look for any memories of my garage.
老天，希望还存在
God, I hope one's still up.
－我们认识的那天 －好恶
- Aw, the night we met. - Gross,
－我的工作台？ －屎光去用…
- on my workbench? - Squanchy used the...
应该去壁橱里的
That's what some closets are for!
拜托，希望你够注重细节
C'mon, I'm really counting on your attention to detail here.
你只记得我的实验室里有这个？
This is what you remember from my lab?
你希望我把你的东西记清楚吗？
You would prefer I keep a mental inventory of your stuff?
对
Yes.
瑞克山查兹，我在此逮捕你
Rick Sanchez, you're under arrest
因为你逼我在地球高中渡过两年
for making me spend two years in Earth high school.
快开车…
Go, go, go!
我们得发挥创意才能离开这里了
We'll have to do some creative memory shit to get out of here.
出口是我们在鸟人艺术祭认识
The exit's when we met at Birding Man
还一起吸毒的时候
and did senthol diempathate.
天啊，真美好的时光
Damn, a great time.
对，太欢乐了
Exactly, it's too happy.
没有路能直通那里
There won't be a clean path to get there.
我们得利用我的记忆开路再一路跳过去
We'll need to build one with memories of mine and lily-pad our way up.
我们有什么共同回忆
What related memories do we share
是充满了愤怒和悲伤的？
heavy on anger and sadness?
齿轮人的丧礼
Geardude's funeral.
确实很悲伤
Oh, that was sad.
因父及子及圣神之名…
Patris et filii, Gearitus Sanctis...
他们只是记忆，开过去，是假的
They're memories, just run them over. They're not real.
等等，那是齿轮头吗？
Hey! Wait, is that Gearhead?
我们跟他哥一起当过自由战士
We were freedom fighters with his older brother.
这是很重要的背景
Hugely important context.
你以为因为好玩才跟他来往吗？
You thought we hung out with him for fun?
我们还需要一座桥才能到艺术节
We need one more bridge to the festival,
还有什么记忆？穿西装的人
what's here? People in suits,
可悲的外烩午餐
sad catered lunch
刚单身的寡妇，表演相关的呢？
newly single widows... Something performance based?
屎光去讲的不得体悼词
Squanchy's very distasteful eulogy.
屎光去的悲剧脱口秀时期
Squanchy's terrible stand-up phase.
这就对了
That's it!
直走
Down that way.
我在屎光去的时候
So you know when you're squanching
她就会很深入
and she just gets real in there.
很下流的屎光去，知道吧？
Y'know that real nasty squanch?
你们在搞…
Who are you... What is...
天啊，我是记忆
Oh my god. I'm a memory.
我们刚刚白听了一堆脱口秀
We just sat through all that stand-up for nothing.
就快到了
Almost out.
听好了，各位，我叫瑞克
OK, listen everybody. My name's Rick.
这位是我的新朋友鸟人
This is my new friend, Bird Man
还有他朋友，我们才刚在这认识
and his friends, we all just met at this festival.
我们太嗨了，所以组了个乐团…
and we're so high we formed a band...
我是不会让你逃走的
As if I'd ever let you escape me.
－活着也没多好 －嘿
- Living's overrated. - Hey!
别忘了我
Remember me!
不，干，我们本来已经扯平了
No, fuck. We were even.
你这个关于我的记忆还算酷
You got a pretty cool memory of me.
我们该走了，兄弟，快动手吧
Go time, pal. Might be time to do the thing.
真抱歉，看来我好像杀了你
I'm sorry for killing you
还把你变成生化人
and turning you into a cyborg, apparently.
我是真的爱过你
I really did love you.
我也爱过你
I loved you too.
再见了，谭美
Goodbye, Tamantha.
快一点，我这样很尴尬
Come on, man. I feel ridiculous.
谢谢你没放弃我
Thank you for not giving up on me.
很好，你现在可以快点报答我
Great, you can pay me back literally right now.
靠，天啊，靠
Holy shit! Wow, holy shit.
我们差点就出不来了
We almost didn't make it.
真他妈太惊险了，太夸张了
Jesus fuck, that was close. That was insane.
天啊，刚刚那样还有那样
Oh my god. That thing with the thing!
谢谢你，瑞克
Thank you, Rick.
等等，我要先跳回我的身体
Wait... let me hop back over to my body.
我们回来了，瑞克和鸟人万万岁
We're back, baby! Rick and Birdperson, a hundred years.
要不要一起喝酒庆祝一番？
What do you think, tie this one off by tying one on?
今天不行，我得去处理孩子的事
Not tonight. I have, as you say, parenting shit to deal with.
对，好吧，欢迎加入我的行列
Right, yeah. Welcome to the club.
不要复制孩子
Don't clone it
然后把其中一个送去外太空
and send one of the two into space.
孩子很讨厌那样
I guess they really hate that.
记忆瑞克好像除掉邪恶谭美
I think Memory Rick ditched Evil Tammy
偷偷躲进我的大脑了
and snuck back over into my brain.
壁橱里有我的青少年记忆
I have a pubescent memory of my older self in my closet.
我得去处理一下，可能会出大事
Gotta deal with that, that could get ugly.
瑞克，我不想自找麻烦
Rick, I do not like to pull threads.
因为准没好事，跟我本性相违背
It is a disruptive and feline activity.
－但我得问你 －没关系，别问
- But I must ask... - It's fine, you don't have to.
你是不是曾经知道我有孩子却选择不告诉我
Was there really a second in there where you knew about my child but chose not to inform me
因为你担心我会为了照顾小孩
on the chance I might then grow too busy childrearing
忙到没空陪你？
to hang out?
你应该要感谢我发现你有孩子
Weird way to thank me for discovering your kid.
你来救我的时候不知道我有孩子
You did not know of the child when you came to rescue me
你知道后还是没告诉我
and once aware, refrained from sharing
直到为了自救，非说不可才说
until necessary to save yourself.
好吧
Fair enough.
我们暂时先别见面了
I will see you when I see you.
什么？那个人在干吗？
What... what is this guy doing?
等等，什么？但你说…
Wait, what? But you said...
快走开，怪人
Get out of here, weirdo!
好奇怪的陌生人
What a weird stranger.
竟然有一个随机的人
Huh, what a random thing to happen.
拿着所有能量储存装置来这里
This guy coming up here with all his energy storage devices.
我承认自己背信了
Disloyalty acknowledged.
没关系，我能理解
Nah, I get it.
我只是在顾小孩
Just babysitting.
还有在客厅试穿我新买的裤袜
That and modeling my new pantyhose in plain view of the living room.
其实孩子来看也没差，我很欢迎
Honestly, if the kid could come watch, I'd welcome it.
这年代的文化不介意，对吧？
This cultural time period's cool like that, y'know?
事情不是你想的那样
It's... not what it looks like.
看来你是从阿鸟的潜意识
It looks like you propagated yourself
跑进了我的潜意识
from BP's subconscious to mine
想继续当有知觉的记忆
to try to live as a sentient memory.
好吧
Fair enough.
你的存在不代表你就是我的敌人
You don't have to be an enemy just because you exist.
我以为你会因为我想活就讨厌我
I did assume you'd hate me for trying to live.
因为你很冷酷无情
You've got this wild callousness thing going on.
是啊，你还年轻
Yeah, you're young.
来，我把你变成真人，一起喝酒
C'mon, let's bring you to life and get a beer.
我变成真人就终究会变成你吗？
Does being real mean I eventually become you?
应该是，对
I assume, yeah.
你还是记得我们一起喝酒就好？
Maybe you can just remember us getting a beer?
嘿，干
Hey! Oh, fuck.
我的天啊
Jesus Christ.
你有没有想过把暴力的人关一起
You ever think putting the violent ones in the same place
可能会造成反效果？
might be counter-productive?
我们的职责不包含思考，费尔
They don't pay us to think, Phil.
对，你是对的，抱歉
No you're right. Sorry.